NIKITA KOSTIN

Espoo, Finland · nskostin96@gmail.com · +358414960156 · https://nik31096.github.io

Profile

Highly initiative and self-motivated machine learning engineer with 6+ years of academic and industry experience. Proficient in Python and has solid knowledge of machine learning algorithms. Proven record of contributions to software development projects from top tech companies. Demonstrated teamwork and supervision skills in several academic and industrial projects.

SKILLS

Software tools: Python, C++, Julia, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Pandas, ROS2, Git, Docker, LaTex. Languages: English (C1), Swedish (B1), German (A2), Finnish (A1), Russian (native).

CERTIFICATES

Generative AI with Large Language Models, Coursera, Jul 2024.

Work experience

Aalto University

Espoo, Finland

Research Scientist

Nov 2021 - Present

- Research in safe and robust reinforcement learning algorithms for robotics.
- Developed uncertainty-aware safe exploration for reinforcement learning using text-based constraints using a Bayesian cost model, making the agent safely operate in complex, unknown environments (under review).
- Developed robust reinforcement learning algorithm for fast adaptation to unseen dynamical changes using adaptive control (under review).

Huawei Research Center

Sep 2019 - Oct 2021

Machine Learning Engineer

- Research and development of deep learning algorithms for image enhancement and super-resolution.
- Developed a deep learning solution for demosaicing of underscreen camera photos that improved the quality of the images.
- Developed a super-resolution algorithm based on Normalizing Flows that improved the quality of the underscreen camera photos.

Samsung R&D Institute

Moscow, Russia

Moscow, Russia

Machine Learning Engineer

Jun 2018 - Aug 2019

- Research and development of automation algorithms for cloud and mobile applications.
- Developed OpenStack system installation automation that speed up the deployment of the system on a new location.
- Developed AI-based Mobile Testing Automation for Android using Reinforcement Learning that accelerated new features testing.

EDUCATION

Aalto University	Espoo, Finland
PhD in Electrical Engineering (not completed), GPA: 4.52	Jan 2022 - Present
Lomonosov Moscow State University	Moscow, Russia
M.Sc in Applied Mathematics, GPA: 4.05	Sep 2018 - May 2020

M.Sc in Applied Mathematics, GPA: 4.05

Lomonosov Moscow State University

Moscow, Russia

B.Sc in Physics, GPA: 4.51

Sep 2014 - May 2018

Conferences and Workshops

Teaching assistant at ProbAI

Helsinki, Finland

Lead TA on Normalizing Flows section of Nordic Probabilistic AI summer school.

Jun 2022

Teaching assistant on RL course TA on the Reinforcement Learning course.

Helsinki, Finland Sep 2022 - Present

International Workshop of Intelligent Autonomous Learning Systems

Kleinwalsertal, Austria

Organized by the Intelligent Autonomous Systems lab from TU Darmstadt.

Aug 2023

Generative Modeling Summit

Belgrade, Serbia

Organized by Yandex, it presented the latest technologies behind YaGPT.

Sep 2023

ELLIS Robust Machine Learning Workshop

Helsinki, Finland

Workshop covered important topics of robustness of ML, LLMs and Human-Computer Interaction.

Jun 2024